终于找到你了
There you are.
瞧瞧发生了什么
Look what happened.
瞧瞧我干了什么
Look what I did.
现在你的故事结束了
Your story is over now.
关于你的一切  我亲手终结了
All of you... I ended it.
但我的故事才刚刚开始
But mine is just beginning.
再见  父亲
Goodbye, Father.
我一直都很爱你
I always loved you...
哪怕你从未爱过我
even if you never did me.
快走吧  女王陛下
Please, my queen.
神抛弃了我们
God has abandoned us!
我们是帕岩子民
We are Payan.
我们是神圣的  我们是天选...
We are holy. We are chosen--
快走  小家伙
Come on, boy.
好了  真乖
Okay. Good boy.
猛兽沉睡太久了
The beast has slept for too long.
现在它醒来了
And now it is awake.
一切都在我们前方
Everything is ahead of us...
一切重要的东西都在前方
everything that matters.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我做了什么
What have I done?
你给了我一点独处的时间
You gave me some time alone.
抗拒了逼问答案的冲动
Resisted the urge to push for answers
哪怕你明知我无法给出答案
you know I can't give.
你父亲给你的哪个小饰品能这么重要
What could be so important about some trinkets your father gave you
以至于你宁愿拿你孩子和丈夫的命去冒险
that you would risk your children's lives, your husband's life...
也要寻回那东西
just to retrieve it?
我敢肯定  如果关于你已经透露了
I'm sure if there were more to that story
故事的更多隐秘
than you've already divulged,
你也会先告诉他们  再告诉我
you would've told them before you would tell me.
不过  我想说...
I will say, though...
还有另外一个问题
there is a different question...
刚刚过去的片刻时间里
I have spent the last little while...
我的大脑始终无法抑制想问的冲动
unable to silence in my mind.
是什么问题
What question is that?
你出现在我们的生命里的那天
The day you arrived in our lives...
你还记得杰拉马瑞尔在离开前
do you remember the last thing
对我说的最后一句话是什么吗
Jerlamarel said to me as he left?
我不记得
I don't.
他说  "要小心"
He said, "Be careful."
在那一刻  以及此后的每一刻
In that moment, and in every moment since,
我都以为他的意思是
I assumed he meant...
"要小心照顾我爱的这个女人
"Be careful with this woman I love,
小心照顾她即将生育的孩子"
with the children she's soon to bear."
他留下的话对我来说如同磐石
His words have been like a rock to me...
坚不可摧  让我多年来一直牢牢记挂着
something solid to hang on to all these years.
但自从我们离开瀑布  踏上这条河流逃亡
But with all that has changed since we left the waterfall
有太多东西都改变了
and set off up this river...
我开始琢磨  我是否误解了他的意思
I wonder if I misunderstood what he meant.
他还能是什么意思
What else could he have meant?
如今你的丈夫和孩子们
Now your husband and children,
手无寸铁地步入巨大的危险中
they have walked unarmed into grave danger
一切只因为你的要求
because you said so.
他们几乎没有迟疑
They hardly hesitated.
你也没有
Nor did you.
我感觉到  自从我们踏上这段旅程
I feel something growing in you
往上游进发后  你的体内有什么东西在疯长
since we started upriver on this journey.
隐藏在你的声音  你的行事方式里  玛格拉
Something in your voice, in your way, Maghra.
令人敬畏
Something formidable.
亦充满黑暗
Something dark.
我还是那个你认识了几乎一辈子的人
I am the same person you've known for almost a lifetime.
我理解你的困惑  我也容忍你的好奇心
I understand your confusion, and I tolerate your curiosity.
但请不要暗示
But please do not suggest
我丈夫和孩子陷入巨大的危险
that my husband or my children are in grave danger
是因为我有邪恶的动机
because of my sinister motives.
或者我不关心他们的死活
Or that I am indifferent to their welfare.
握住我的手
Hold my hand.
跟我一起祈祷
Pray with me...
祈祷他们都能平安无恙地回来
that they'll all come back safe and unharmed.
这些可能是踩踏出来的路
These might be tracks here.
哪里
Where?
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
你们听到了什么
What do you hear?
什么都没有
Nothing.
我听到哼唱声
I hear humming.
没错
Yes.
有一群人  他们都在哼唱
A bunch of people, and they're humming.
从那个方向传来
Coming from that way.
哼唱  谁在哼唱
Humming? Who's humming?
哼唱
Humming.
这是什么
What is this?
奥派罗族  拾荒者
Opayol. Scavengers.
下面根本没人  看上去像是废弃了
There's no one down there. It looks deserted.
并没有
It isn't.
他们晚上出来活动  白天躲着睡觉
They're about by night, and they sleep by day.
就是他们拿走了我们的东西
They're the ones who took our things.
他们绝对就在下面
They're most definitely down there.
但我不知道具体有多少人
What I can't say is how many men.
我猜他们的人数比我们多得多
I'm guessing there's a lot more of them than there are of us.
-那是自然  -我们不能回去
- Easily. - We're not turning back.
我猜他们的武器也比我们多得多
I'm also guessing they're a lot less unarmed than we are.
不管你妈的东西有多重要
Whatever the significance of your mother's possessions,
我相信她肯定不会希望你们任何一个为此丧命
I am certain she would not want either of you dead over it.
我同意
Me too.
但我可以悄悄潜入再出来
But I can get in and out of there
完全不被他们察觉
without them even knowing I was there.
任何人都不准单独行动
No one's going anywhere alone.
我必须单独行动
I have to go alone.
那样我才最不可能被抓到
I'm least likely to get caught that way.
我可以偷偷溜进溜出
I can slip in and out.
你自己也说了  大白天他们很可能在睡觉
You said so yourself, they're probably asleep.
但只要你吵醒一个  其他人也很快会聚过来
But if you wake one of 'em, the other ones will come out quickly.
那我就避开他们
Then I'll avoid them.
妈妈心里清楚要找到那东西会有多困难
Mama knew how difficult it would be to find this,
但她还是请求我们这么做
and she's asked us anyway.
难道我们认为她不知道这意味着什么吗
Are we saying that we don't trust her to understand what that means?
还是说我们认为
Are we saying we think
她无法做出那样的决定
she's incapable of making that kind of decision?
好吧
Okay.
你们两个都在这里
You're both right here.
如果我需要帮助  我会大喊
I'll call out if I need help.
但我必须一试
But I have to try.
这主意糟透了
This is a terrible idea.
不  我们应该阻止她的
No, we should've stopped her.
怎么阻止
How?
她会为我们任何一个人这么做的
She would've done this for any one of us.
我们任何人都阻止不了她
She would not have been stopped by any one of us.
说真的  我觉得这跟我们都没有关系
Honestly, I don't think this has anything to do with us.
我觉得从妈妈提到她父亲的那一刻起
I think the moment that Mom mentioned her father,
以及她跟他的情感联系
her connection to him,
哈妮瓦就已经做出了决定
Haniwa's decision was made.
其实也根本不需要做什么决定
You know, there wasn't even a decision to be made.
而是不可避免的事实
It was unavoidable.
一想到缺位的父亲
The idea of an absent father,
有可能重续父女情的机会
the chance to reconnect,
那就...
it was just...
过于贵重  对她来说难以承受
It was too much for her.
我只怕不会有...
And I'm just afraid that there's not gonna be--
不好
Oh, no.
哈妮瓦
Haniwa!
哈妮瓦  哈妮瓦
Haniwa. Haniwa.
-她还有呼吸吗  -有
- Is she still breathing? - Yeah.
-她伤到了哪里  -我看不出来
- Where's she hurt?  - I can't see.
爸爸
Dad!
等等  不  等等  不要
Wait. No. Wait. No, no!
不要  住手
No. Stop.
住手  你不知道他是谁
Stop! You don't know who he is!
我不管他是谁
I don't care who he is!
他的胸膛
His chest.
你看  触摸  触摸一下
Look. Feel. Feel.
起来  给我起来
Get up. Get up.
他也能看得见
He can see.
这里空荡荡的
So empty here.
我出生在发动机的轰鸣声中...
I was born into the sound of the engines...
雷鸣  权势
thunder, power...
意义
meaning.
我这一辈子都浸在其中
I spent my entire life bathed in it.
从未远离过都城  远到听不见那些声音的地方
Never ventured far enough from the capital that I couldn't hear it.
我一直很好奇
I always wondered
如果我再离开得远一点  世界会是什么样的的声音
what the world would sound like if I'd ventured a little... further.
结果发现  根本就没有什么特殊的声音
Turns out, sounds like nothing at all.
真是无趣得令人难以置信
How unbelievably boring.
您听水的声音  女王陛下
Listen to the water, my queen.
以及风的声音
And the wind.
或许如果您仔细听  就能听到它在对您耳语秘密
And perhaps if you listen, it might whisper its secrets to you.
这里才没有什么秘密
There are no secrets here.
没有信息
No information being bargained.
没有故事
No stories being woven.
没有力量  没有恐惧
No strength, no fear.
空无一物
Nothing.
普通人都是这样生活的吗
Is this really how people go about their lives...
生命中全无任何重要的东西
in the absence of anything of any importance?
我想是吧  女王陛下
I suppose so, Your Majesty.
这趟旅程或许需要这么做
This journey may require it,
但我觉得恐怕我不擅长做普通人
but I don't think I'll be very good at being that person.
我觉得自己恐怕没有一丝地方
I don't believe there's even the smallest part of me
能适应这种生活
that is built for it.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
I'm hungry!
我准备好用餐了
I'm ready to take my dinner.
你找到蛋了吗  现在正是产蛋的季节
Did you find eggs? 'Tis the season.
车夫
Driver?
我听到火快要熄灭的声音  你找到食物了吗
I hear the fire dying. Did you find food?
车夫  你在哪儿
Driver, where are you?
快把火烧起来  它快要被自己的烟弄熄灭了
Save the fire. It's choking on its own smoke.
车夫
Driver?
车夫  你他妈回个话
Driver? Fucking answer me.
纳丽
Nyrie!
Nyrie.
纳丽
Nyrie!
你们想要什么我都有
I have whatever you want.
你们想要什么我都有  我有戒指  有神骨
I have whatever you want. I have rings. I have God bone.
真柔软
So soft.
纤巧的手指
Exquisite fingers.
不要戒指
No rings.
不要神骨
No God bone.
我们要带你走
We take you.
纳丽
Nyrie?
Nyrie!
妈妈  是我们
Mama, it's us.
哈妮瓦
Haniwa.
来
Come.
你找到了吗
Did you, did you find it?
谢谢
Thank you.
我数到四个人
I count four.
我们的新朋友是谁
Who is our new friend?
他们叫他博资
They call him Boots.
浣熊会躲起来
Raccoon hides.
偷我们东西的家伙就是他
This is the creature who took our things.
是的
Yes.
但是他不知道我们是谁  他没得选
But he didn't know who we were, and he didn't have a choice.
请让我解释
Let me explain, please.
好
All right.
杰拉马瑞尔离开我们后
When Jerlamarel left us,
就像他承诺的那样  离开我们去了觉悟大宅
left us to go to the House of Enlightenment as he promised...
但他似乎没有直接去那里
it seems he didn't go there directly.
他停下过冬
He made a stop for the winter.
他去找了奥派罗族
He approached the Opayol.
和他们住了一年
He lived among them for a year.
一年
A year?
但是他的孩子一出生
But... once his child was born...
他就继续上路了
he resumed his journey.
博资就是那个孩子
Boots is that child.
博资是杰拉马瑞尔的儿子
Boots is Jerlamarel's son.
我们的弟弟
Our brother.
在杰拉马瑞尔继续上路之后
After Jerlamarel continued his journey...
奥派罗族人把博资当奴隶来使唤
the Opayol treated Boots like a slave.
逼他替他们拾荒和偷东西
Forced him to scavenge and steal for them.
当有消息传来
Once word came that the
说猎巫者在搜查这一带时
Witchfinder was campaigning through this area,
奥派罗族离开了这里  去别处寻求安全
the Opayol left to seek safety elsewhere.
他们把他丢在这里  让他自生自灭
And they abandoned him here to fend for himself.
孩子  孩子
Child! Child!
你是说我们带他一起走吗
Are you suggesting we bring him along with us?
是的
Yes.
除了可以让他不必
Aside from offering him a way out
再被人当做动物来对待
of being treated like an animal...
而且他对我们来说很有用  技艺高超的战士
aside from him being an asset to us, a skilled fighter...
他能看见
He can see.
是吗
Can't he?
对  他能看见
Yes, he can see.
你们俩都同意吗
You two, you are in agreement?
为什么每个人都这样
Why is everyone being like this?
他是我们的家人  我们不会弃他不顾
He is family. We're not leaving him behind.
我已经问过你所有想问的问题了
I've asked all the same questions you have.
我也有同样的担忧
I have expressed the same concerns.
然后呢
And?
如果我不同意这件事  帕丽丝
And if I was gonna forbid this from happening, Paris,
我想你现在早就听到我的反对了
I imagine you would have heard me do it by now.
对吧
Don't you?
你还知道他别的什么情况
What else do you know about him?
除了他高明的偷窃之术
Aside from his skill as a thief.
你相信他吗
Do you trust him?
从来没人这样照顾我
I have never had anyone to look after me
像你们那样彼此照顾
as you do for each other.
如果能成为你们的一份子
To be a part of that,
我愿意做你们吩咐的一切
I will do whatever it is you ask of me.
那就让他一起走吧
Then let him come.
让我们开始为自己组建一支视觉大军
Let us begin to build for ourselves an army of the sighted...
只要新招募的士兵
so long as its newest recruits are willing
愿意宣誓效忠我们当中唯一的将军
to swear their allegiance to the only general we have amongst us.
我宣誓效忠
I swear it.
不  证明给我们看
No. Show us.
真是完美的一天
Such a perfect day.
我觉得你的沉默不言
Your total silence I find
比她的沉默不言更有意思
far more interesting than her total silence.
他们撕裂你们的喉咙时  我一定会在场
You know, I will be there when they slit your throats,
提醒你们今天犯了一个多么离谱的错误
reminding you what a fucking mistake you made today.
与你分离了太多次
Too many times separating from you...
总担心那会是我们最后一次见面
and worrying it'll be our last.
我们再也不要分开了
Let's never do it again.
我从来没跟你提起过他
I never told you much about him...
关于我父亲
about my father.
我从来没叫你说
I never asked you to.
你的出身对我来说不重要
It's never mattered to me where you come from.
我知道  你也是
I know. Nor I you.
他死的那天把这个交给我
He gave this to me the day he died.
从他记事起  他家人就拥有这个东西
Been in his family for as long as he could remember.
打开吧
Open it.
不惜一切就为了找回这个
All of that for this.
你一定肯定很爱他
Must've loved him very much.
他是个非常好的人
He was a very good man.
善良  聪明
Kind, wise.
如果他还健在在  他一定会喜欢你
I think he would've liked you.
别高兴过头了
Let's not get carried away.
真希望我认识他
I wish I'd known him.
也许改天你可以和我多说一点他的事
Perhaps you can tell me more about him sometime.
我很乐意
I think I'd like that.
可风说得对
Kofun is right.
我该上路了
I should get moving.
当然
Of course.
那孩子  博资
That boy, Boots...
你不信任他  对吗
you don't trust him, do you?
我最近不打算相信任何新来的人
I haven't planned on trusting anyone new for a while.
明白了
I see.
那你为什么准许这件事
Then why did you choose to allow it?
你认为我在这件事上还有选择  真让我受宠若惊
I'm flattered you thought I have any choice in the matter.
我是认真的
I'm being serious.
-我知道  -那你为什么不阻止
- I know. - Why didn't you forbid it?
因为在旅程的终点...
'Cause at the end of this journey...
他们将见到一位新的父亲
they will meet a new father.
我不能再给他们任何新理由来渴望他了
And I can't give them any new reason to want one.
可风理解我们的选择
Kofun understands our choices.
他总是这样
He always has.
不会把这事往心里去
Doesn't take them personally.
但她...
But her...
我不想失去她
I don't wanna lose her.
你不会
You won't.
也许吧
Yes.
我爱你
Love you.
他们不喜欢我  是吗
They don't like me, do they?
他们很害怕
They're scared...
还很困惑
and confused.
但他们是好人  他们会回心转意
But they're good people. They'll come around.
他们喜欢你吗
Do they like you?
你在说什么
What did you say?
他们对你大喊大叫
They yell at you.
他们质问你  让你觉得卑微
They question you, make you feel small.
我的族人就是一直这样对待我
That is how my people always treated me.
他们为什么要让你戴着面具
Why did they make you wear the mask?
他们说我不像他们
They said I was not like them.
不是一个人  而是别种东西
Not a man, but something else.
他们说面具会提醒着我
They said the mask would remind me.
我的家人爱我
My family loves me.
他们并不总是理解我
They don't always understand.
但我从来没有质疑过他们对我的爱
But I have never doubted for one moment that they love me.
你受到的待遇  是错误的
How you've been treated, it was wrong.
你值得更好的生活
You deserve better than that.
但我保证...
But I promise...
你现在是我们的一员了
you're one of us now.
你再也不会遭受那种境遇了
You'll never be treated that way again.
你母亲
Your mother.
你觉得她还有余力去爱另一个孩子吗
Do you think she will have room to love another child
像爱你和你哥哥一样
as she already loves you and your brother?
那可能需要一些时间
That may take some time.
这对她来说很复杂
This is complicated for her.
但是...
But...
我妈妈是我见过最有爱心的人
my mother has the biggest heart of anyone I've ever met.
她做正确的事
She does what's right.
她总是做正确的事
She always does what's right.
你为什么要保守自己的秘密那么久
Why did you keep your secret for so long?
你怎么做到的
How do you do that?
做什么
Do what?
偷袭那些能看到你偷偷摸摸的人
Sneak up on people who can see you sneaking up on people.
我不是想偷偷摸摸
I wasn't trying to be sneaky.
也许你只是没注意到
Maybe you just weren't paying attention.
你能回答我的问题吗
Will you answer my question?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
什么秘密
What secret?
你守护了这么久
You kept it for so long,
甚至都不知道这是个秘密了
you don't even know it's a secret anymore.
为什么艾肯尼没有人知道...
Why did no one in the Alkenny know...
你们能看见
that you could see?
当猎巫者出现时
Well, given how everyone else reacted
考虑到其他人的反应
when the Witchfinder turned up,
我想我父母不告诉他们
I think my parents were probably wise
是个正确的选择
to not trust them with that piece of information.
巴巴和玛格拉被困在了艾肯尼
Baba and Maghra were stuck in the Alkenny.
我想他们守护了一个秘密来保护你们俩
And I guess they kept a secret to protect you two.
差不多是那样  没错
Something like that, yes.
我能告诉你观察那些不知道
Can I tell you what it's like to observe people
你在观察他们的人是什么感觉吗
that don't know that you're observing them?
对你来说  他们无比脆弱
They are completely vulnerable to you.
你可以守住他们的秘密
You could keep their secrets.
你可以把它们传播给敌人
You could spread them to their enemies.
你可以击打他们...
You could strike at them...
但他们永远不可能知道是谁干的
without them ever knowing who did it,
或怎么做的  或其中原因
or how, or why.
你可以改变他们的生活
You could change their life.
可以终结他们的生命
Could end their life...
不管任何理由...
for any reason...
或者根本没有理由
or no reason at all.
神便是如此
That is what gods do.
你可能不知道这是什么感觉
You might not know what this feels like
因为你从来没选择去左右他人
because you never made the choice to hold that power over others.
这个决定你父母替你做了
It was made for you by your parents.
但我知道
But I know.
我想杰拉马瑞尔也知道
And I suspect Jerlamarel knew, too.
对我来说  这能让我更亲近我跟踪的人
For me, it brought me closer to those I shadowed.
对于杰拉马瑞尔...
For Jerlamarel...
他在他们中间生了一个孩子  抛弃了他
he fathered a child among them and abandoned him.
那么  这些跟你有什么关系
So, what does any of this have to do with you, anyway?
或许我觉得这很有趣  你能看到
Maybe I find it amusing that you can see
但仍察觉不到
and still observe so little.
我在哪里
Where am I?
虫城
The City of Worms.
我在哪里
Where am I?
我的朋友们
My friends.
你们带了什么给我
What have you brought me?
我有一匹马  它需要水
I have a horse. It needs water.
我累了  我要睡觉
And I'm tired. I need to sleep.
我赶了一整天的路
I've ridden all day.
我要油来擦屁股  还有抹油的女仆
I need oil for my ass and a maid to apply it.
等我睡醒后  再跟你说话
After I've slept, I will speak to you.
你犯了个大错
You've made a mistake--
纤巧的手指
Exquisite fingers.
你们干得不错  谢谢  她非常完美
You have done well. Thank you for this. She will be... perfect.
蚕是一种神奇的动物
A silkworm is a fascinating creature.
你想知道为什么吗
Would you like to know why?
它出生时如此微小  无暇  谦逊
She begins so small, so innocent, unassuming.
但在它短暂的一生中
But in the course of her very short life,
它创造了如此美丽完美的丝
she creates a substance of such beauty, such perfection,
让世界上最富有的男人
that the wealthiest men in the world,
能够为自己  为妻子  为小妾
men who could dress themselves, their wives, their concubines,
披上绫罗绸缎的男人
in whatever they desire,
为此趋之若鹜
choose... this.
当它的生命到尽头时  它的功效用尽
And when her life has run its course, her usefulness expired,
在它最后的年岁丑陋蜷曲
she spends her final days sadly grotesque.
这种带翼的动物渴望飞翔
A winged creature with the urge to fly
却始终未使用这个能力
but denied that ability.
蚕茧用尽
A husk of herself, used up,
渴求死亡
eager for death.
你会在这慢慢了解它
You will come to know her well here.
你会慢慢理解它
You will come to understand her.
我的朋友  你不希望我在这里
My friend, you do not want me in here.
我这辈子都没遇见过虫子
I haven't met a worm in my life.
没错  也许它能让你一时心欢
Yeah. Perhaps for a time, it'll amuse you.
但很快你会后悔
But soon you will regret it!
是吗
Is that so?
你是何方神圣  竟敢放出如此獗言
I wonder who you might be to make such a claim.
纤细的手  没干过重活
Delicate hands unused to being worked.
粗鲁不恭的嘴  未遭受过惩罚
An impudent mouth unused to being struck.
富裕的女人
A woman of wealth...
习惯于搬弄权力
accustomed to wielding authority
或也许是她丈夫的权力
or the authority of a husband, perhaps.
但从哪而来
But from where?
猎巫者不久前来过这里
The Witchfinder's campaign brought him through here not long ago.
当他询问信息时
When he was asking for information,
他的口音让我想起了自己在坎祖瓦的年月
his accent reminded me of the time I spent in Kanzua,
把商品卖给钱多得没处花的上等贵族
selling our goods to the high-born with money to burn.
你的口音也让我想起那段过去
Your accent brings back those same memories.
我猜你是个贵族
You were a noblewoman, I presume.
也许甚至是那个贱人女王的议会成员
Perhaps even a councilor to that bitch queen.
但无论如何
But no matter.
在这你和其他人一样  或甚至更不值一提
Here you will be the same as the rest, or even less so, perhaps,
因为一切都要从头学起
as everything must be learned from the beginning.
如果你为我努力工作  就能活得好
If you work hard for me, you will live well.
如果你想逃跑  你也逃不远
If you try to escape, you will not get far,
而后果将会
and the consequences will be...
不堪设想
unpleasant.
你是个有趣的人
You are an interesting one.
我很期待和你度过
I look forward to whatever time
我们在一起的时间
we are able to spend together here.
聆听我的声音
Hear me...
杰拉马瑞尔
Jerlamarel.
可风
Kofun?
我在这里  爸爸
Yeah. Here, Dad.
船松开了吗
Is the boat free?
是的  但被卡住了
It's unmoored, but it's stuck.
什么卡住了  被卡在哪里了
What do you mean "stuck"? Stuck where?
退潮了
Tide's gone out.
我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我们只能等早上了
We're gonna have to wait till morning.
快来
Come.
快跑
Run.
过来
Come.
快跑
Run.
他们没法穿过森林  对吧
They can't ride through this, can they?
他们可以  但会减慢他们的速度
They can. But it'll slow them down.
我听见他们了
I hear them.
-哈妮瓦  -我在
- Haniwa. - Yes.
带你妈妈和帕丽丝去安全的地方
Take your mother and Paris and find shelter for them.
我爱你  快去
I love you. Go. Go.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
爸爸  我跟你在一起
Dad, I'll stand with you.
是的  儿子
Yes, you will, son.
待在这里
Stay here.
一切都会没事的
Everything will be all right.
玛格拉
Maghra?
巴巴沃斯
Baba Voss!
妈妈呢  怎么了
Where's Mama? What happened?
-她不见了  -哈妮瓦
- She's gone. - Haniwa!
-哈妮瓦  -不
- Haniwa. - No.
巴巴  我之前握着她的手
Baba, I had her by the hand.
他们抓走了她
They took her?
不  她自己放开了我的手
No, she let go of my hand.
她在我耳边低语  她说"要小心"
She whispered to me. She said, "Be careful."
妈妈
Mama?
Mama!
塔玛奇俊
Tamacti Jun!
你听见我的声音了吗  猎巫者
Do you hear my voice, Witchfinder?
你听见了吗
Do you hear me?
说话
Speak.
猎巫者
Witchfinder...
你能听见吗
can you hear me?
我听见了一个死人的声音
I hear the voice of a dead woman.
那你好好听听
Then listen closer.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
并告诉大家
And speak.
万岁
Hail...
玛格拉公主
Princess Maghra...
凯恩家族的玛格拉公主
of the House... of Kane.
下跪敬礼
Give homage!